Register of the Greek Subject Collection, 1913-1984
Hoover Institution Archives
Greek Subject Collection,
1913-1984
XX756
3 manuscript boxes (1.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
The collection consists of correspondence, reports, notes, pamphlets, leaflets, newsletters, and other printed matter, relating to miscellaneous aspects of twentieth-century Greek history, and especially to relief aid to Greece after World War II, the Greek civil war, and the military junta installed in Greece in 1967 and opposition to it.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Greece.; World War, 1939-1945--Civilian relief.; International relief.; Greece.; Greece--History.
Collection Contents
- Subject file, 1913-1970 (Folder 1-2)
  - Otho I, 1832-1862. "Greek Society and Politics under King Otho, 1843-1862," by J. K. Campbell, 1960 (Folder 1: 1)
  - Greeks in Albania, 1913, "Memorandum of the Epirotes of the District of Korytza to the Ambassadors at London in 1913" (Folder 1: 2)
  - Civil War, 1945-1949 (Folder 1)
    - Atrocities. Pamphlet on atrocities committed by the communists during the civil war, 1945 (Folder 1: 3)
      In Greek, English, and French
    - Relief activities. Reports, newsletters, pamphlets, and leaflets, relating to relief activities in Greece during and after World War II, 1945-1947. (Folder 1: 4-7)
      Includes issuances of the Greek War Relief Association and of the American Mission for Aid to Greece. In English and Greek
  - Greek Political Opposition, 1967-1970 (Folder 1-3)
    - Statements by various Congressmen on the Greek political situation and entered in the Congressional Record; extracts from the Record, 1969-1970 (Folder 1: 8-10)
    - Statement by Constantine Hadjidimoulas on uniting the resistance, 1970 (Folder 1: 11)
    - Reports on the Greek situation by the Council of Europe, Consultative Assembly, 1968 (Folder 1: 12-14)
    - Letters from Congressmen and Senators to Henry P. Durkin on the Greek situation, 1970 (Folder 2: 1)
      Includes appeals to resist, press releases, statements, and communiqués from Athens Committee of Democratic Defense, 1968
    - Athens wire service releases on the Greek political situation, 1968 (Folder 2: 2)
    - Greek political opposition buttons distributed by Amnesty International, U.S.A. (5 buttons) (Folder 2: 3)
    - Torture reports, 1968 (Folder 2)
      - By the Greek Committee Against Dictatorship, 1968 (Folder 2: 4)
      - "Visit to Athens," by Michael Chambers, 1968 (Folder 2: 5)
      - "Notes on a 'Trial' of 21 Greek Democrats," by the Democratic Defense Center Union Organization, 1968 (Folder 2: 6)
      - "Information on the Torture of Political Prisoners in Greece since the Military Coup of April 21, 1967,", 1968 (Folder 2: 7)
      - Situation in Greece, by Amnesty International, London, 1968 (Folder 2: 8)
      - Miscellaneous reports, 1968 (Folder 2: 9)
    - Periodicals, pamphlets, books, and handbills on the Greek political situation, 1967-1970 (Folder 2)
      - Greek Report, 1969 (Folder 2: 10)
      - Greece Today, 1968 (Folder 2: 11)
      - Amnesty Action, 1967-1968 (Folder 2: 12)
      - News of Greece, 1968 (Folder 2: 13)
      - Press Reports on Greece, 1970 (Folder 2: 14)
      - Poreia, 1968 (Folder 2: 15)
      - Demokratia, 1968 (Folder 2: 16)
      - Courrier de la Grèce, 1968 (Folder 2: 17)
      - Three Years of National Resurgence, 27 April 1967 - 21 April 1970, Athens (Folder 2: 18)
      - Greece - a New Vietnam? by Elias P. Demetracopoulos, 1968 (Folder 2: 19)
      - A Handbook of Democracy, Athens, 1970 (Folder 2: 20)
      - Yearbook on International Communist Affairs, 1968, Hoover Institution Press, 1969 (Folder 2: 21)
      - "Greek Dictatorships and 'Free Elections'," by George Anastaplo, 1968 (Folder 2: 22)
      - "James Pondopoulos 000, Licensed to Torture," by James Becket, circa 1968 (Folder 2: 23)
      - Book review by Dwight James Simpson on Barbarism in Greece, by James Becket, circa 1970 (Folder 2: 24)
    - U. S. and foreign magazine and newspaper articles and clippings from San Francisco Chronicle, Manchester Guardian, New York Times, National Observer, Washington Post, Christian Science Monitor, National Review, Commonweal, Intercom, Amnesty International Review, and others, 1967-1970 (Folder 3: 1-14)